在本次讲座中，
In this lecture,
我们将学习使用 CSS 设置文本样式的六个属性。
we will learn about six properties to style text with CSS.
让我们快速回顾一下
And let's just quickly recap
我们在上一节课中做了什么。
what we did in the last lecture.
所以我们在这个 CSS 文件中编写外部 CSS
So we are writing external CSS in this CSS file
并且 CSS 文件总是由多个 CSS 规则组成。
and the CSS file is always composed of multiple CSS rules.
所以现在我们只有一个 CSS 规则，
So right now we only have one CSS rule,
但是，当然，我们现在将开始添加更多。
but, of course, we will now start adding more of them.
现在，CSS 规则总是以选择器开头。
Now, a CSS rule always starts with a selector.
所以在这种情况下，我们选择 h1 元素，
So in this case, we are selecting the h1 element,
但是如果有更多的 h1 元素，
but if there were more h1 elements,
那么选择器实际上会选择所有这些。
then the selector would actually select all of them.
然后我们在这里有这个声明块
Then we have this declaration block here
我们可以在其中写入一个或多个声明
into which we can write one or more declarations
像这个
like this one
每个声明都有这个属性名称。
and each declaration has this property name.
所以在这种情况下，颜色，
So in this case, the color,
然后是我们为该属性指定的值，
and then the value that we specify for that property,
在这种情况下，这是蓝色的这个关键字。
which in this case is this keyword of blue.
所以现在我们将开始在这里添加更多属性。
And so now we will start adding some more properties here.
我要使用的第一个是字体大小。
And the first one that I want to use is the font size.
所以这里我们基本可以指定文字的大小
So here we can basically specify the size of the text
每个属性可以采用不同类型的值，
and each property can take different types of values,
例如长度或关键字。
such as length or keywords.
所以你看到这里的颜色，值是一个关键字，
So you see that here in the color, the value is a keyword,
但是现在在字体大小中，我们实际上需要一个长度。
but now here in the font size, we actually need a length.
所以基本上，在这种情况下，文本的大小。
So basically, the size of the text, in this case.
现在我们可以在 CSS 中使用不同的单位来指定长度，
Now we can specify length using different units in CSS,
但现在不要担心。
but don't worry about that for now.
所以现在，我们将简单地使用最简单的一个，
So for now, we will simply use the very simplest one,
这是屏幕上的像素。
which is pixels on your screen.
所以我们可以指定字体大小，比如26像素，
So we can specify the font size, for example, 26 pixels,
然后在此处添加分号。
then add a semi-colon here.
所以现在屏幕上的文字
And so now the text on the screen
将恰好是您物理屏幕的 26 像素。
will be exactly 26 pixels of your physical screen.
所以如果我现在给这个保存，
So if I give this a save now,
然后你会看到这里的文字减少了。
then you see that the text here decreased.
只要记住，以防它没有更新
And just remember that in case it didn't update
在您的计算机上，您已成功连接
on your computer and you are successfully connected
到实时服务器，你可以在这里看到，
to the live server, as you can see down here,
然后只需在此处手动重新加载页面一次。
then just manually reload the page here once.
然后在这里成功更新代码，
And then in the successful updates here of the code,
然后它将自动重新加载您的页面。
it will then automatically reload your page.
但无论如何，现在让我们开始添加下一个属性，
But anyway, let's now start adding the next property,
这是字体系列。
which is the font family.
所以在这里你可以指定
And so here you can specify
您的文本的基本不同的字体。
basically different fonts for your text.
所以就像你可以指定一个字体
So just like you can specify a font
在 Word 文档或 Google Page 文档之类的文件中，
in something like a Word document or a Google Page document,
你可以在 CSS 中做同样的事情。
you can do the same in CSS.
但是，在 CSS 的情况下有什么不同
However, what's different in the case of CSS
是你不能简单地使用字体系列
is that you cannot simply use a font family
您已在计算机上安装的
that you have installed on your computer
因为那不适用于所有用户
because that wouldn't then work for all the users
将来会访问您的页面，
that are going to visit your page in the future,
除非他们还在计算机上安装了该字体。
unless they also have that font installed on the computer.
所以有一个解决方案
So there is a solution for that
我们稍后会谈到，
that we will talk about later,
但现在我们根本不会实际指定
but for now we will simply not actually specify
一个真正的字体系列，但只使用关键字
a real font family, but instead just use the keyword
我们希望浏览器使用任何字体大小
that we want the browser to use any font size
那是无衬线字体。
that is a sans serif.
还有无衬线字体，我们以后也学一点
And sans serif, we will also learn a little bit later
这实际上意味着什么，
what that actually means,
所以在本课程的设计部分，
so in the design section of this course,
但如果我们现在挽救一下，
but if we give this now a save,
你看到这里的字体完全变了。
you see that this font here changed completely.
所以现在看起来更干净了，
So now it looks more clean,
但重要的是现在当我们更新我们的页面时，
but what matters is that now as we update our page,
事实上，这个标题的字体系列
in fact, the font family here of this heading
现在看起来很不一样。
now looks very different.
所以它不再有这些衬线，
So it no longer has these serifs,
就像这里的这些小东西
which are like these small things here
在字母的末尾。
at the end of the letters.
再一次，稍后，在设计部分，我们将学习
And again, later, in the design section, we will then learn
我们如何为我们的页面指定特定的字体系列。
how we can specify specific font families for our pages.
但是现在让我们来看看我们的下一个属性
But now let's take a look at our next property here
对于文本，即文本变换。
for text, which is text transform.
因此，对于文本转换，
And so with text transform,
我们基本上可以将文本转为大写。
we can basically turn a text uppercase.
所以你可以再看一次，
So you can see, one more time,
VS Code 在这里给了我们很多建议，
the VS Code gives us a lot of suggestions here,
所以这整个清单。
so this whole list.
所以这里最常用的实际上是大写的。
And so the most used one here is actually uppercase.
所以大写，像这样，
So uppercase, like this,
结果正是您所期望的。
and the result is exactly what you would expect.
所以所有的文字都变成了大写。
So all the text simply turn uppercase.
所以这是一个简单的。
So this is a simple one.
现在让我们尝试另一种称为字体样式的方法。
And now let's try another one which is called font style.
在这里，您再次看到这些选项。
And here again, you see these options.
在这种情况下，最常用的一个，
The most used one, in this case,
是将一些文本设置为斜体。
is to set some text to italic.
所以让我们检查一下，
So let's check that out,
事实上，这正是发生的事情。
and indeed, that is just what happened.
因此，正如预期的那样，文本变成了斜体。
So the text turned italic, as expected.
太好了，所以我们已经介绍了四个属性
Great, so we already covered four properties
以及这里的一些可能值。
and some of its possible values here.
所以我们正在取得良好的进展。
So we're making good progress.
当然，正如我之前提到的，你没有
And of course, as I mentioned before, you do not have
现在开始在这里记住这些属性。
to start memorizing these properties here now.
随着时间的推移你会习惯它们
You will get used to them over time
随着您开始越来越多地使用它们。
as you start using them more and more.
让我们在这里真正摆脱其中的一个，
And let's actually get rid one of this one here,
因为我们实际上会谈论颜色
because we will actually talk about colors
稍晚一些。
a little bit later.
好的，现在让我们进入下一个标题。
Okay, so let's now go to our next headings.
所以现在让我们为我们的 h2 元素设置样式。
So let's now style our h2 element.
这就是本文的主要标题。
So that is this basically main heading of this article.
所以我们可以使用我们已经学习过的属性。
And so we can use the properties that we already learned.
因此，如果您继续输入这些属性名称，
And so if you keep typing these property names,
他们会开始进入你的大脑。
they will start getting into your brain.
所以这个，让我们实际上让它比h1更大。
So this one, let's actually make it even bigger than the h1.
非常大，像40像素，
So really big, like 40 pixels,
这完全没有问题。
and that's no problem at all.
所以仅仅因为 h1 是页面的主标题，
So just because the h1 is the main heading of the page,
这并不意味着它也必须是最大的。
it doesn't mean that it also needs to be the biggest one.
所以成为 h1 真的是关于语义，
So being the h1 is really all about semantics,
不仅仅是关于它的外观。
not only about what it looks like.
所以我们有一个很好的大文本
So we have a nice big text
现在让我们让它也无衬线，
and now let's just make it also sans serif,
所以给它这种现代的外观和感觉。
so giving it this modern look and feel.
所以无衬线关键字，
So the sans serif keyword,
现在我们开始。
and here we go.
接下来让我们为段落设置样式。
Next up let's style our paragraphs.
所以，正如我之前提到的，
And so, as I mentioned before,
通过像这样选择 p 元素，
by selecting the p element like this,
这实际上将选择所有 p 元素
this will actually select all the p elements
在我们的页面上。
that are on our page.
所以这一段在这里和这个和这个，
So this paragraph here and this and this,
以及我们在页面上的所有内容。
and really all the ones that we have here on the page.
所以让我们再给它一个字体大小，
So let's give it again a font size,
假设是 22 像素。133
let's say of 22 pixels.
而现在，所有这些长度，
And for now, all of these lengths here,
所以我一直在使用的所有这些数字
so all of these numbers that I've been using
有点随机，
are kind of random,
但稍后我们还将学习如何使用系统
but later we will also learn how we can use a system
这样我们就可以基本自动
so that we can basically automatically
找出我们应该使用的字体大小。
figure out which font sizes we should use.
现在我也想再次更改字体系列，
Now I also want to change the font family again,
再一次，使用无衬线字体，
and once again, using sans serif,
很好，看起来已经很不错了。
and nice, that looks very nice already.
如果我们将它与我们的演示进行比较，
And if we compare it with our demo,
然后我们可以看到我们开始越来越近
then we can see that we start getting closer
到，或者是，到我们的演示页面，
to, or yeah, to our demo page,
所以我们到底想要达到什么。
so what we want to achieve in the end.
实际上只有一件事
There is actually just one more thing
我想在这些段落中进行更改，
that I want to change here in the paragraphs,
这是指定另一个新属性，
which is to specify yet another new property,
这是行高。
which is the line height.
所以我将首先实际指定它。
So I will first actually specify it.
然后你会看到文字的不同。
And then you will see the difference in the text.
所以这里我们实际上使用了一个没有单位的值。
So here we actually use a value without a unit.
所以在这种情况下，这个 1.5 只是意味着
So in this case, this 1.5 simply means
行高将是字体大小的 1.5 倍。
that the line height will be 1.5 times the font size.
所以默认情况下，行高只是一，
So by default, the line height is simply one,
但是现在如果我们将其设置为 1.5，那么您应该会看到空间
but now if we set it to 1.5, then you should see the space
这里的字里行间增加
between the lines here increase
在这里和这里和这里之间。
between here and here and here.
所以仔细看看我现在点击这里
So look closely at that as I now click here
重新加载页面，
to reload the page,
你会发现这真的改变了。
and you'll see that really changed.
当然，我们可以将它设置得更高，
And we could set it even higher, of course,
然后我们会得到更多的空间，
and then we would get even more space,
但已经看起来有点太多了。
but already looks a bit too much.
所以让我们回到 1.5，像这样。
So let's go back to 1.5, like this.
现在，顺便说一句，这里发生了一件很有趣的事情
Now, by the way, something quite interesting happened here
也许你注意到了。
that maybe you noticed.
所以记住这些段落的内部
So remember how inside of these paragraphs
我们刚刚设计的，我们有不同的元素
that we just styled, we have different elements
比如这个斜体字，
such as this italic text,
哪个是 em 元素，记得吗？
which is an em element, remember?
所以在这一段中，
So here in this paragraph,
例如，我们有 em 元素，
for example, we have the em element,
或者在本段中，我们有强大的元素。
or here in this paragraph, we have the strong element.
或者在这里我们有锚，
Or down here we have the anchor,
所以这个元素就在这里。
so this element right here.
如您所见，页面上的这些元素，
And as you can see, these elements here on the page,
例如，这里的锚点
so for example, this anchor here
不知何故得到了相同的字体大小
somehow got the same font size
以及与 p 元素相同的字体系列，
and the same font family as the p element,
即使我们没有指定这些样式
even though we did not specify these styles
对于任何地方的链接。
for the link anywhere.
所以我们没有指定字体大小和家族
So we didn't specify the font size and the family
和线高，而不是锚点，
and the line height, not for the anchor,
不适合强文本，
not for strong text,
或不适合强元素，
or not for strong elements,
也不适用于 em 元素。
and also not for the em element.
但是他们仍然以某种方式将这些样式应用于他们。
But still they got these styles applied to them somehow.
以及这样做的原因
And the reason for this
是一种非常重要的机制，叫做继承。
is a very important mechanism called inheritance.
现在理解起来有点复杂。
Now this is a little bit complex to understand.
所以我们会有一个完整的讲座
And so we will have a whole lecture
稍后关于继承，
on inheritance a little bit later,
但我仍然想向你展示这种效果
but still I wanted to already show you this effect
在这一点上在这里行动。
in action here at this point.
但无论如何，让我们现在继续设计或提醒元素。
But anyway, let's now keep styling or reminding elements.
所以从h3开始，
So starting with h3,
让我们把它放在 h2 之后
and let's put that here after the h2
以合乎逻辑的方式将我们的规则分组。
to group our rules here in a logical way.
所以这个字体的大小，让我们把它设为 30 像素。
So the font size in this one, let's make it like 30 pixels.
所以这将是这个，确切地说。
So that's going to be this one here, exactly.
和这个。
And this one.
同样，我们有多个 h3 元素。
So again, we have multiple h3 elements.
所以在这里使用 h3 选择器，
And so by using the h3 selector here,
我们将选择所有这些。
we will select all of them.
现在，又是字体系列，
Now, just the font family again,
并将其设置为无衬线字体。
and setting it to sans serif.
好的。
All right.
现在终于有了 h4 标题。
And now finally, we have the h4 heading.
所以这就是这里。
So that's this one here.
所以让我们再次设置字体大小
So let's again set the font size
和字体系列，
and the font family,
所以20像素
so 20 pixels
这里是无衬线字体。
and here sans serif.
实际上，我们也将这里的文本转为大写。
And actually, let's also turn the text uppercase here.
并记住我们如何使用文本转换属性
And remember how we use the text transform property
为了那个原因。
for that.
如果我们像这样将其设置为大写，
If we set it to uppercase like this,
好的。
nice.
现在只有一个最终属性
And now there is just one final property
我想向你展示基本的文本样式，
that I want to show you to basically style text,
也就是说我们也可以对齐文本。
which is that we can also align text.
再说一次，有点像我们可以在 Microsoft Word 中做的
So again, a little bit like we can do in Microsoft Word
或在谷歌页面或类似的东西。
or in Google Pages or something like that.
因此，我们使用文本对齐属性。
And so for that, we use the text align property.
同样，您可以在此处查看选项。
And again, you can see the options here.
我们可以使用的一个有趣的
One interesting one that we can use
就是让文字居中对齐。
is to align the text to the center.
那么猜猜当我保存它时会发生什么？
And so guess what will happen now when I save it?
好吧，我们需要再去这里
Well, we need to go down here again
你会看到它现在位于页面的中心。
and you see that now it is in the center of the page.
从技术上讲，它位于其父元素的中心，
And technically it is in the center of its parent element,
但是那个父元素基本上占据了整个页面，
but that parent element basically occupies this entire page,
因此它现在位于页面的中心。
and so therefore it is now at the center of the page.
好的。
All right.
所以现在我们唯一缺少的东西
And so now the only thing that we are missing
这些列表项在这里。
is these list items here.
所以这五个和这三个，
So all of these five and these three,
还有这些锚点，所以链接，
and also these anchors, so the links,
但我们稍后会为链接设置样式
but we will style the links a little bit later
因为链接有一些特殊情况。
because there are some special cases for links.
所以让我们结束这个视频
So let's just finish this video
通过设置这些 li 元素的样式。
by styling these li elements.
好的。
All right.
让我们在这里做，
Let's do that down here,
并注意我们如何不设置 ol 元素的样式
and notice how we do not style the ol element
和 ul 元素
and the ul element
它们是列表项的父元素。
that are the parent elements of the list items.
所以请记住，列表本身是一个 ol
So remember that the list itself is an ol
或者它是一个 ul，
or it is a ul,
但我们确实设置了 li 元素的样式。
but we do actually style the li elements.
再一次，让我们设置字体系列，
And so again, let's set the font family to something,
实际上，无衬线字体也是如此。
so to sans serif, actually.
给它一个保存。
Give it a save.
我们还想再更改一次字体大小。
And we also want to change the font size one more time.
所以默认情况下，我们会得到这里看到的字体大小，
So by default, we get this font size that we see here,
默认情况下通常为 16 像素。
which is usually 16 pixels by default.
所以这是很重要的事情
So that's an important thing
我们也需要稍后知道。
that we also need to know a little bit later.
所以请注意这一点。
So take note of that.
但当然，我们想让它更大一点。
But of course, we want to make it a little bit bigger.
所以我们的段落是 22 像素。
So we have our paragraphs at 22 pixels.
所以让我们把它缩小一点。
So let's actually make this a little bit smaller.
假设是 20 像素。
So let's say, at 20 pixels.
就是这样。美丽的。
And that's it. Beautiful.
所以我们完成了页面文本的基本样式，
So we finished the basic styling of our text of our page,
在此过程中，我们了解了六个新的 CSS 属性。
and we learned about six new CSS properties along the way.
所以花点时间回顾一下我们刚刚做了什么，
So take some time to review what we just did,
然后让我们继续下一节课
and then let's move on to the next lecture
我们将在这里学习更多关于选择器的知识。
where we will learn a little bit more about selectors.